Guess who's coming to save the world again?
Ghostbusters II is a comedy, fantasy film directed by Ivan Reitman.
The discovery of a massive river of ectoplasm and a resurgence of spectral
activity allows the staff of Ghostbusters to revive the business.
Peter Venkman, played by Bill Murray.
Ray Stantz, played by Dan Aykroyd.
Dana Barrett, played by Sigourney Weaver.
Dr. Egon Spengler, played by Harold Ramis.
Louis Tully, played by Rick Moranis.
Winston Zeddemore, played by Ernie Hudson.
Ghostbusters II is a 1989 American supernatural comedy film directed by
Ivan Reitman and written by Dan Aykroyd and Harold Ramis.
The film stars Bill Murray, Aykroyd, Sigourney Weaver, Ramis,
Rick Moranis, Ernie Hudson, and Annie Potts.
It is the sequel to the 1984 film Ghostbusters and the
second film in the Ghostbusters franchise.
Set five years after the events of the first film, the Ghostbusters have been sued and put out of
business after the destruction caused during their battle with the deity Gozer the Gozerian.
When a new paranormal threat emerges, the Ghostbusters
reunite to combat it and save the world.
After the success of Ghostbusters, Columbia Pictures wanted a sequel but
struggled to overcome objections from the cast and crew.
As with the first film, Aykroyd and Ramis collaborated on the
script, which went through many variations.
The pair wanted to convey a message about the consequences
of negative human emotions in large cities.
They settled on the idea of negative feelings creating a mass of supernatural
slime beneath New York City that empowers malevolent spirits.
With a budget of $30–40 million, filming took place between November
1988 and March 1989 in New York City and Los Angeles.
Production was rushed and large sections of the film were
scrapped after poorly received test screenings.
New scenes were written and filmed during re-shoots between March
and April 1989, only two months before its release.
Ghostbusters II was released on June 16, 1989, to generally negative reviews.
Critics responded unfavorably to what they perceived as largely a copy of the original and a softening of its cynical, dark humor to be
more family-friendly, although the performances of Peter MacNicol and Rick Moranis were repeatedly singled out for praise.
As the sequel to the then-highest-grossing comedy film of all time,
Ghostbusters II was expected to dominate the box office.
Instead, the film earned $215.4 million during its theatrical run compared with the
original's $282.2 million, making it the eighth-highest-grossing film of the year.
Columbia Pictures deemed it a failure, effectively dissuading
Murray from participating in a third Ghostbusters film.
Its soundtrack single, "On Our Own" by Bobby Brown, was a success,
spending 20 weeks on the United States music charts.
The film failed to replicate the cultural impact and following of Ghostbusters and was seen as
responsible for stalling the franchise for decades, though its reception has improved over time.
The film spawned a series of merchandise including video games, board
games, comic books, music, toys, and haunted houses.
Despite the relative failure of Ghostbusters II, a second
sequel was pursued through to the early 2010s.
Following the mixed reviews and financial underperformance of the 2016 series reboot, the series returned to the
original film canon with Ghostbusters: Afterlife (2021) and Ghostbusters: Frozen Empire (2024).
The film explores themes of new year's eve, new york
city, painting, supernatural, ghostbuster.
The tone is lighthearted.